<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
    <link>http://mkar.ch/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mitchell Karchemsky</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mkar.ch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bifröst | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/bifr%C3%B6st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/bifr%C3%B6st/</guid>
      <description>Abstract A key challenge in developing and debugging custom embedded systems is understanding their behavior, particularly at the boundary between hardware and software. Existing tools such as step debuggers and logic analyzers only focus on software or hardware, respectively. Bifröst is a new development environment designed to illuminate the boundary between embedded code and circuits.
Bifröst automatically instruments and captures the progress of the user’s code, variable values, and the electrical and bus activity occurring at the interface between the processor and the circuit it operates in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Practices | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/teaching/criticalpractice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/teaching/criticalpractice/</guid>
      <description>The Course Critical Practices is taught under the Berkeley Center of New Media. A hybrid course which focuses not only on the history and theory behind revolutionary installations and pieces, but invites the students to practice. As evident in the course title, a core tenant of the class is the critical view which must be taken by the students to embrace and offer cultural critique through the use of art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dalmatian | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/dalm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/dalm/</guid>
      <description>Dalmatian In the Fall of 2016, I enrolled in the class &amp;ldquo;Interactive Device Design&amp;rdquo; with Björn Hartmann and took on the project of creating better response technology for emergency personnel. We interviewed with firefighters all around the San Francisco Bay Area, and we found that the hardest part of their job was communication.
 We understood that only about 20% of radio communications are fully understood between both parties: the incident commander who handles the situation from a van outside the scene, and the firefighter on the scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heimdall | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/heimdall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/heimdall/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Students and hobbyists build embedded systems that combine sensing, actuation and microcontrollers on solderless breadboards. To help students debug such circuits, experienced teachers apply visual inspection, targeted measurements, and circuit modifications to diagnose and localize the problem(s). However, experienced helpers may not always be available to review student projects in person. To enable remote debugging of circuit problems, we introduce Heimdall, a remote electronics workbench that allows experts to visually inspect a student’s circuit; perform measurements; and to re-wire and inject test signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wifröst | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/wifr%C3%B6st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/wifr%C3%B6st/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The rise in prevalence of Internet of Things (IoT) technologies has encouraged more people to prototype and build custom internet connected devices based on low power microcontrollers. While well-developed tools exist for debugging network communication for desktop and web applications, it can be difficult for developers of networked embedded systems to figure out why their network code is failing due to the limited output affordances of embedded devices. This paper presents WiFröst, a new approach for debugging these systems using instrumentation that spans from the device itself, to its communication API, to the wireless router and back-end server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Within2 | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/within2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/within2/</guid>
      <description>Background Within 2 was a project I worked on with Meyer Sound, The Berkeley Center for New Media, and Artist Tarek Atoui. We started with the question of &amp;ldquo;How do we create music for the hearing impaired?&amp;rdquo; A quote by Stanford Professor Anne Fernald guided me throughout the project:
 &amp;ldquo;Sound is touch at a distance.&amp;rdquo;
 How can we rethink music in such a way that brings it to a more visceral physical sensation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Innovation 22 | Mitchell karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/teaching/des22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/teaching/des22/</guid>
      <description>The Course Design Innovation 22 primarily serves as the fundamental foundation for students to have success in future Design Innovation Courses. With a heavy emphasis on creativity, iteration, and design, this course lays the groundwork to rapid prototype ideas with a combination of traditional and digital fabrication tools
Design Innovation 22 is a demanding course. The corpus of students leans more heavily towards first semester freshmen but will also attract upperclassmen due to the creative nature of the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MakerPass | Mitchell karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/makerpass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/makerpass/</guid>
      <description>The Challenge Authenticating users for any space is a very difficult task. In a community like the Jacobs Hall Makerspace and the CITRIS Invention Lab, it is imperative for users to be properly trained and authorized to use the equipment and spaces. To solve this problem, Eldon Schoop, Chris Myers, and Björn Hartmann, developed the Makerpass system. This allows for students to use their existing Cal ID (school distributed Identification card) to &amp;ldquo;badge in&amp;rdquo; to authenticate their access to the location, or equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invention Lab | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/teaching/inventionlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/teaching/inventionlab/</guid>
      <description>The CITRIS Invention Lab supports faculty, student and community innovation by providing the knowledge, tools and support to rapidly design and prototype novel interactive products, embedded sensing systems and integrated mobile devices. This facility is a vital piece of the CITRIS pipeline running from the minds of researchers through CITRIS laboratories, and into the markets, industries, and streets of the world. The Invention Lab offers a variety of prototyping equipment ranging from basic craft tools to electronics workbenches, CAD stations and professional digital fabrication machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doom Sense | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/doom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/doom/</guid>
      <description>Doom Sense Doom Sense was a project done in the class &amp;ldquo;Software Defined PCBs.&amp;rdquo; The class focused on the idea of using software to define which components need to be utilized in order to bridge the gap in creating hardware. Being a student of Cognitive Science, I wanted to incorporate what I had learned about neuroplasticity to see how adding an additional sense modality would affect ones performance.
We modeled our device around the first person shooter DOOM, where it is important to always be tracking what resources you have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drill Sergeant | Mitchell karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/drill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/drill/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Woodworking tutorials are commonly used to gain proficiency with power tools. However, these tutorials&amp;rsquo; goals generally aim to assist users with constructing an end product, as opposed to developing their confidence and technique with tools.
We present an ecosystem of smart tools which helps users gain confidence, develop technique, and construct woodworking projects by providing guidance and feedback through skill-building activities and macros of common building tasks. We demonstrate how such techniques are enabled by augmenting common workshop tools (drill/driver, saw) with measurement, state sensing, and visual feedback, and describe the design space of such augmentations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strands | Mitchell Karchemsky</title>
      <link>http://mkar.ch/studies/strands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 03:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mkar.ch/studies/strands/</guid>
      <description>Strands Strands was an extension of the Within 2 art project I collaborated with artist Tarek Atoui. In the exploration of generating different timbres and creating instruments which give physical feedback, I designed the Strand board. Emulating stalks of wheat in a field, you can stroke your hand through the acrylic rods, creating frequencies of different pitch(x direction), volume(y direction), and timbre(magnitude of oscillation created by spring back in the individual stalks).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>